A Guide to the Gravely Family Papers, 1753-1988
Library of Virginia
- Series XII: Photographs and negatives
  - Subseries 1: Photographs
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 109, Folder 15)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 109, Folder 16)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 109, Folder 17)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 109, Folder 18)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 109, Folder 19)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 109, Folder 20)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 109, Folder 21)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 109, Folder 22)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 109, Folder 23)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 109, Folder 24)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 109, Folder 25)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 109, Folder 26)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Canada and New England) (Box 110, Folder 9)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Nova Scotia) (Box 110, Folder 10)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Nova Scotia) (Box 110, Folder 11)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Rockland, Maine) (Box 110, Folder 12)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Cuba) (Box 110, Folder 13)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Cuba) (Box 110, Folder 14)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Cuba and Florida) (Box 110, Folder 15)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Florida) (Box 110, Folder 16)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Florida) (Box 110, Folder 17)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Miami, Florida) (Box 110, Folder 18)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Miami, Florida, and the Grand Canyon) (Box 110, Folder 19)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (Blackfish) (Box 110, Folder 20)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (25 June 1936) (Box 110, Folder 21)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 17)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 18)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 19)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 20)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 21)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (general images and scenes) (Box 111, Folder 22)
    - Fernald, Benjamin Gravely (envelopes) (Box 111, Folder 23)
    - Kearfott family (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - Semple family (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Gravely, Annie (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Ashland, Virginia (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - Martinsville, Virginia (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Martinsville, Virginia (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - Martinsville, Virginia (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - Martinsville, Virginia (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - Martinsville, Virginia (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - Martinsville, Virginia (Box 112, Folder 10)
    - People (Box 112, Folder 11)
    - Martinsville, Virginia (Box 112, Folder 12)
    - Seaboard Air Line Railroad Station, Middlesburg, North Carolina (Box 112, Folder 13)
    - Henry County, Virginia (Box 112, Folder 14)
    - Lee County, Virginia (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Patrick County, Virginia (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - Surry County, Virginia (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Jamestown Exhibition (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - Orange, Virginia (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - Luray, Virginia (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - People (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - Black workers, unidentified (Box 113, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified scenes (Box 113, Folder 9)
    - People unidentified (Box 113, Folder 10)
    - Trips to Michigan and Ohio (Box 113, Folder 11)
    - Photograph name and subject indexes (Box 113, Folder 12)
    - Photograph name and subject indexes (Box 113, Folder 13)
    - Daguerrotypes (Box 114)
    - Photograph albums of the Kearfott family (Box 115)
    - Photograph albums of Julia Alberta Gravely Fernald (Box 116)
    - Postcards (Box 116)
    - Photograph album of Annie Gravely (Box 117)
    - Scrapbook of Eva Lurita Stone (Box 117)
    - Paul Gravely scrapbook, 1899 (Box 118)
    - Paul Gravely scrapbook, 1906-1918 (Box 118)
    - Paul Gravely scrapbook, of World War II, including obituaries (Box 118)
  - Subseries 2: Negatives and Contract Prints, 5 x 7
    Includes photographs from Remsen Studios of the following people and families: Iris C. Atkins, Claude Barker, Doug Bassett, Berlin family, Connie Blue, Mr. Bolejack, W. Richard Broaddus, W. Richard Broaddus, III, J. Amon Brodie, Mary Brown, Mrs. James Carter, Edward T. Cheshire, Jesse D. Clift, Ms. Clift, Mr. Dalton, Robert Daniel, Mitchell Davis, Ursie Davis, Jack C. Dodge, Priscilla H. Dudley, Mr. Earles, S. Burdell Eure, Robert J. Fagg, Mr. Finney, Lee Ford, Mr. Fountain, William Franck, Mr. Globman, Mrs. Hund Goode, Irving Miller Grovers, III, Mrs. Irving Miller Groves, Sr., Mrs. Irving Miller Groves, Jr., Ruth D. Groves, Mrs. Haynes, R.A. Henderson, George T. Hennessey, Hermann family, Eldon W. Holsinger, Mabel B. Hooker and Children, May Hooker, Ralph A. Hooker, Grey C. Hughes, Oliver V. Huskey, Grace James, T.K. Jones, Jr., William Jones, Harry B. Kester, Natalie P. Lester, W. Alfred Mays, Eugene M. McDaniel, Steve L. Mitchell, Jr., James O. Nance, Pannill wedding, Mary Lavinder Pannill, John G. Ragland, Benjamin S. Ramsey, J.D. Ripple, Warren Robinson, Mike Sale, Shackelford family, Jesse M. Shackelford, John W. Shumate, Charlotte O. Simmons, Charles Smith, Dudley Smith, John Redd Smith, Randolph Smith, David T. Stanford, Bill Stone, Mary B. STone, Mr. Stowe, Jack Townes, John W. Townes, Claude S. Turner, H. Kenneth Whitner, Midred Windley, Mr. Witt, Mr. Woody, Bob Atkins, Mrs. Jones, Mrs. W.D. Jones, George T. Lester, Sr., Mr. Fountain, Abe Globman, Irving Miller, Groves, Jr., Charles E. Reed, Walter E. Roadcap, Jr., Mr. Ruffin, Ed Whitner, and Honlu E. Broaddus.
    - (Box 119 and 120)
  - Subseries 3: Negatives, 5 x 7
    Includes negatives of the following people, families, and places: William Charles Sunday school class, Ed Draper, Mr. English, Golfers, Charles A. Hall and daughters, R.A. Henderson, Harry B. Kester, Martinsville High School class, Townes Funeral Home, Nina S. Whitener, John Letcher Englhis, Clarence P. Kearfoot, Dick Lee, Robert S. Pannill, Edwin G. Penn, Lucy Moir Pannill Brown, Chalres H. Davis, D.S. Davis, Draper Barber Shop, Edgar H. Draper, Geoffrey Draper, George W> Draper, Harry Draper, W.R. Draper, Jesse Ben Gregory, Jim Kester, Harry M. McMillion, Tom Moore, Wes Shumate, Creed STone, George Turner, Frank Winn, Lewis Winn, Raish Winn, W. Burton Dillon, A. Frank Hooker, J. Clyde Hooker, Sr., Hooker-Bassett Furniture Company, Myron E. Whitener, Sr., Globman's Dept. Store, Martinsville flood, Edwin G. Penn, Jr., H. Banks Pannill, Girl Scouts, and the Martinsville Police.
    Also includes negatives from Remsen Studios of the following businesses, people, places, and families: Altrusa Club, William W. Ascough, William C. Barnes, Murray B. Barrow, Bassett Furniture Co., Pat Brown, Byrd Building, Coleman Supply Co., Corner-Ston Apt., Cross Laundry Co., Billy Cross, Fred Cross, Jack D. Cross, Irvin W. Cubine, Mr. Daughton, David S. Davis family, Ed Davis, Jr., Ed Draper children, Gustave B. Dudley, W. Brown Dudley, Esso Service Center, Robert J. Fagg family, Fieldale Mills, John Floyd, Thoms M. Ford family, Mattie H. Groves, Guld Super Service (Church and Moss Streets), Charles A. Hall family, Mr. Hatcher, Hermann family, Hermann studio, Francis A. Hermann, Ms. Hermann, W. Wallace Hermann, Chevis Horne, Frank Hundley, Alphonso Krupski, Garland T. LaPrade, Lacy-Pannill wedding, Mr. Mannis, Martinsville High School graduation, Martinsville street scenes, Robert L. Mason, McBryde family, Edd McCormicky, H. Grady Moore, National Theatre, Percy C. Nowlin, Pannill-Stephens wedding, A.L. Philpott, Post office, Martinsville post office under construction, Prillaman family reunion, Irving W. Ramsey, Broomfield Reed, Charles W. Reed, Henry C. Reed, Remsen family, Reubel Remsen, E. W. Reynolds, Lena M. Richardton, Carrie Davis Roadcap, Mr. Russell, Schottland family, Finley Schottland, Dr. Shackelford and grandchildren, Jesse M. Shackelford, Mr. Shackelford, Dr. Shelburne, Russell Shumate, Dick Simmons, Dr. Simmons, R. Morgan Simmons, Mrs. Spencer's house, Ms. Stanford, T.B. Stanley, John A> Stephens, Steve Mitchell's Wholesale Auto Parts Store, Mary B. Stone, Mr. Stone, Harold W. Stultz, Dr. Teague, Tennis match, Mr. Thomasson, O. Fletcher Thomasson, Kay Thompson, Townes Funeral Home, Zella D. Townes, Virginia Electrical Supply Co., Mr. Walker, H. Kenneth Whitner family, Mrs. M.E. Whitner, Whittle family children, William Charles Sunday School Class, Dr. Womack, Martinsville High School students, Robert A. Fontaine, Russell Shumate, Girl Scouts, Hermann family, W. Nicholas Ruffin, Abe Globman, John Simmons, Myron Edward Whitener, Jr., Mary Walker Robbins, Margaret S. Simmons, Tony Remsen, and John Simmons.
    - (Box 120)
  - Subseries 4: Negatives, 4 x 5
    Includes negatives of the following people, families, and places: B and P charter members, Martinsille High School football team, First Baptist Church, Beaver Crrek house, Valuable buildings lots for sale broadside, CCC Camp (Ridgeway aerial), Fieldale YMCA, Fieldcrest Mills, Forest Park houses, Henry Hotel and radio tower, Ice on lake, Martinsville houses, Martinsville power plant and dam, Martinsville "Liberty Heights", Post office construction, Dr. Simmons family, Tobacco warehouse, Martinsville flood, John R. Smith house on W. Church street, Santa Claus Parade on Church street, Charity League, Court House Square, Farmers Warehouse tobacco sales, Henry County Court House, Lee Telephone Company, Martinsville, Churches, Stanley Aaron, J. Connie Bouldin, Clark Brown, Gasoline ration stickers on vehicles, Curtis D. Givens, Alice W. Gravely house on Cleveland Ave., Lester airport, Brook Price, World War II posters, "Crazy" Alice, Martinsville on Broad and Cleveland Avenues, Martinsville public square, Thomas C. Matthews, Hugh N. Dyer, Heck A. Ford, Thoams M. Ford, Andy Griffith, Jacques S. Hackler, George T. Lester, Charles Moore, "Crazy" Mose, Flora R. Whittle, "Happy Jack" Plaster, Thomas M. Ford, Jr., Earl Hartley, Brent Remsburg, Awilda M. Roach house, Flora R. Whittle, World War II recruiting posters, Billy Cross, Irving Grove, Charles Moore, Jacque Hackler cabin in Pittsylvania County, Tom Joiner, Jones Creek, Thoams C. Matthews, John Redd Smith, Ruth G. Winn, and a Ford V-8 car from 1934.
    Also includes negatives from Remsen Studios of the following businesses, people, places, and families: Albert Harris High School, American Furniture Company, Bassett Superior, Chatham Heights Baptist Church, City Lake, Daily Bulletin, W. Burton Dillon house, Elks Home, Fairy Stone State Park, Fieldale Methodist Church, G. M. Finley, Stanford C. Finney store, First Methodist Church, First National Bank in Collinsville, Forest Park Presbyterian Church, Frank's Food Fair, George's Super Market, Globman's Dept. Store, W. Donald Hartford, Homecoming queen, Hooker-Bassett Furniture Co., J.D. Bassett Manufacturing Co., Koger Coal Co., Inc., Lee Ford Camp for Boys, Lester Lumber Co., Lynwood Golf Club, Marrowbone Creek, Martinsville "Chatham Heights", Martinsville High School, New Martinsville High School gym, Mratinsville High School shop class, Martinsville Public Library, martinsville aerial, Mayfair shop, McBryde family, Moorman family, Patrick County Hospital, Patrick Henry school, Philpott Lake, Piedmont Trust Bank on Church and Ellsworth streets, Rapid Transit Co., Robert Gair Co., Sale Knitting Co., Snow, St. Joseph Chapel, Standard Garments Inc., Stanley Co., Stone Funeral Home, Towne House Motel aerial, United Elastic Co., W.M. Bassett Furniter Co. fire, Samuel S. Walker house, Virginia D. Walker house on Mulberry Rd., Judge Whittle, Yeaman house, Yeaman-Pannill wedding, Forest Park houses, Lee Telephone Co., Martinsville High School students, Martinsville High School football team, Tony Remsen house "Remhurst", Bassett Forks, Fieldale City Plant, Globman's Dept. Store, Hillis Memorial Baptist Church, Martinsville street scenes, Municipal parking lots, Charles Philpott house aerial, Bassett Mirror Co., Fairy Stone State Park, New Martinsville houses, Albert Harris High School, Axton High School class, Lee Ford Cmap for boys, Pure Oil Co., Ridgeway High School class, Drewry Mason High School, General Hodge memorial service, Troxler Furniture Co., Piedmont Trust Bank on Church St. at Walnut St., Mary S. Whittle family, Philpott dam, J. D. Bassett Furniture Co., Lake Lanier, Stanley Furniture Co., Mabry Mill, Whittle house, Martinsville street work, Black man, Martinsville buildings, H. Irvine Tuggle family, Airport, Albert Harris High School senior play, Antique cars, Armory, Beaver Creek house, Blue Ridge Airway, Christ Episcopal Church, Ridgeway Church, First National Bank, Harry Gravely, Highway 58, House moving, Jeb Stuart Day, Kearfott building, Lake Lanier dredging, Lynwood pool, Martinsville congested traffic, McCabe Memorial Baptist Church, Moonshine still, Paarfus, Jinks and children, John Pace airplane crash, Patrick Henry marker, Pumpkin patch, Sewer disposal plant, Sontag school, Stuart (Va.) buildings, Black female teacher, Tobacco sales, Tourist House, Walker pool, Hartford family house aerial, Helms family house aerials, Henry County map, Lester family house aerial, King family house, Business and Professional Womens Club, Lesco Homes, Lee Telephone Co., George Morris family, and First Presbyterian Church choir.
    - (Box 121 and 122)
  - Subseries 5: Negatives, glass, 4 x 5
    Includes negatives of the following people and families: Julia Alberta Gravely Fernald, Francis Cox Gravely, H.C. Gravely house, Hope Thomas Gravely, Nancy Watkins Gravley, Virginia Leatherwood, Unidentified woman, Benjamin F. Gravely, Mrs. H.C. Gravely, Benjamin F. Gravely, Harold Gravely, Hope Gravely, Paul Gravely, Harold Gravely, Mr. Austin, B.F. Gravely and Sons Tobacco Factory, Barrow's Mill, Black man, Charles Irving Blair, Mr. Calder, Cattle, Clouds, Mr. Crump, Danville and Western Railroad Station in Stockton, Woodberry Forest School dormitory, Gus Dyer, Mrs. Fernald, Ferns, Flowers, Mr. Frazier, mr. Gibson, Benjamin F. Gravely, George Gravely's house, Richard Pleasants Gravely, Harden Hairston, Mr. Johnson, Larkin (black worker), Lester Tobacco Factory, Log barn, Log cabin house in Stockton, Madison Mills dam, Mart Mannering, Mr. McMurran, Mills, Pinkard's Mill, Woodberry Forest School pump house, Mr. Putney, Railroad locomotive, Railroad station in Stockton, Rapidan River, Rocky Branch, Sauer's Mill, Mr. Shackelford, Alfred Simms, Elsie Simms, Mrs. Simms, Mr. Slaydon, Snow, Virginia Stockton, Sunset, Archer Thomas, Katherine Thomas, Mary Ann Starling Thomas, Mr. Thomas, Pine trees, Mr. Turnbull, Jessie Turner, Unidentified children, Mr. Walker's house, Woodberry Forest School, Woods, Tollie Wyatt, Dog, Flowers, Martinsville, Faith Thomas Parrott, Ridgeway, Smith River, Decorated table, Cemeteries, Granberry Methodist Church, Starling family coat of arms, Black man, Black man with scythe, Mounted fish, Grnad Canyon, Horses, C.Y. Thomas, Unidentified boy, Unidentified man and two girls, Unidentified man and woman, Unidentified woman and girl, and Automobiles.
    - (Box 123-125)
  - Subseries 6: Negatives, glass, 5 x 7
    Includes negatives of the following people and families: Unidentified man, woman, and girl, Churches, Granberry Methodist Church, Benjamin F. Gravely, Francis Cox Gravely, H.C. Gravely house, Harold Gravely, Hope Thomas Gravely, John Thomas Gravely, Julia Caroline Thomas Gravely, Nancy Watkins Gravely, Paul Gravely, Gravely, Richard Pleasants, Leatherwood Primitive Baptist Church, Virginia Leatherwood, North Fork Church, B. F. Gravely and Sons Tobacco Factory, Black man, Bonduran'ts Mill, Cascade, Farm, Flowers, Girl, Henry County (Va.), House, Mills, Tobacco boxes, Black nurse, Lewis Gravely Pedigo, Snow scene, and Mary Anne Reamey Thomas.
    - (Box 126 and 127)
  - Subseries 7: Negatives and prints
    Includes negatives and prints of photographs taken by B. G. Fernald and members of the Gravely family.
    - (Box 128-132)